It's six o'clock in the morning,
كانت الساعة السادسة صباحاً،
pitch black outside.
والظلام دامس في الخارج.
My 14-year-old son is fast asleep in his bed,
وكان ابني البالغ من العمر 14 سنة مستغرقا في نومه،
sleeping the reckless, deep sleep of a teenager.
في نوم هانئ وعميق لطفل من عمره.
I flip on the light and physically shake the poor boy awake,
أنرت الغرفة وحركت الطفل المسكين لأوقظه،
because I know that, like ripping off a Band-Aid,
لأني أعلم بأن الأمر كخلع السن،
it's better to get it over with quickly.
من الأفضل الانتهاء من الأمر بسرعة.
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
I have a friend who yells "Fire!" just to rouse her sleeping teen.
لدي صديقة تصرخ "النار!" لتوقظ أبناءها النائمين.
And another who got so fed up
وأخرى طفح معها الكيل.
that she had to dump cold water on her son's head
فتصب الماء البارد على ابنها في السرير
just to get him out of bed.
فقط لتقتلعه من السرير.
Sound brutal ...
قد يبدو الأمر قاسياً...
but perhaps familiar?
لكن ربما مألوف؟
Every morning I ask myself,
أنا أتساءل كل صباح،
"How can I --
"كيف يمكنني --
knowing what I know
معرفة ما أعلمه اليوم
and doing what I do for a living --
وأفعل ما أقوم به للعيش --
be doing this to my own son?"
أن أقوم بذلك لابني؟
You see,
تتخيلون الصورة،
I'm a sleep researcher.
أنا باحثة في النوم.
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
So I know far too much about sleep
أنا أعلم الكثير عن النوم
and the consequences of sleep loss.
وعواقب قلة النوم.
I know that I'm depriving my son of the sleep he desperately needs
أعلم بأني أحرم ابني من نوم يحتاجه بشدة
as a rapidly growing teenager.
نظرا لنموه السريع.
I also know that by waking him up
كما أنني أعلم أنه بإيقاظه.
hours before his natural biological clock tells him he's ready,
ساعات قبل أن يدق جرس ساعته البيولوجية معلنا أنه حان وقت استيقاظه،
I'm literally robbing him of his dreams --
أنا أنتزعه نزعا من أحلامه --
the type of sleep most associated with learning, memory consolidation
ذاك الطور من النوم المرتبط بالتعلم وتقوية الذاكرة
and emotional processing.
والعملية العاطفية.
But it's not just my kid that's being deprived of sleep.
لكن ليس طفلي لوحده من يحرم من النوم.
Sleep deprivation among American teenagers is an epidemic.
أصبح الحرمان من النوم وباء متفشي بين المراهقين الأمريكيين.
Only about one in 10 gets the eight to 10 hours of sleep per night
فقط 1 من 10 يحصل على 8 إلى 10 ساعات من النوم بالليلة الواحدة
recommended by sleep scientists and pediatricians.
التي يوصي بها علماء النوم وأطباء الأطفال.
Now, if you're thinking to yourself,
الآن، إن كنتم تتساءلون،
"Phew, we're doing good, my kid's getting eight hours,"
"هاه، نحن نقوم بعمل جيد، "إن طفلي ينام 8 ساعات،"
remember,
تذكروا،
eight hours is the minimum recommendation.
8 ساعات هي الحد الأدنى الموصى به.
You're barely passing.
أنتم تقفون على الهاوية.
Eight hours is kind of like getting a C on your report card.
فالنوم 8 ساعات هو كالحصول على درجة متوسط في نتيجتكم.
There are many factors contributing to this epidemic,
هناك العديد من العوامل المساعدة في تفشي هذا الوباء،
but a major factor preventing teens from getting the sleep they need
لكن العامل الأساسي في حرمان المراهقين من الحصول على كفايتهم من النوم
is actually a matter of public policy.
متعلق في الواقع بسياسة عمومية.
Not hormones, social lives or Snapchat.
ليس مشكل هرموني أو حياة اجتماعية أو سناب شات.
Across the country,
فالعديد من المدارس
many schools are starting around 7:30am or earlier,
عبر البلاد تبدأ دوامها حوالي 07:30 صباحا أو أبكر،
despite the fact that major medical organizations recommend
بالرغم من حقيقة أن أكبر المنظمات الصحية توصي
that middle and high school start no earlier than 8:30am.
بأن المدارس الاعدادية والثانوية لا تبدأ دوامها قبل 08:30 صباحاً.
These early start policies have a direct effect on how much --
سياسات الدوام المبكر تلك تؤثر بشكل مباشر على --
or really how little sleep American teenagers are getting.
أو كم أن المراهقين الأمريكيين يعانون من قلة النوم.
They're also pitting teenagers and their parents
إنها تضع المراهقين وأباءهم
in a fundamentally unwinnable fight against their own bodies.
في معركة خاسرة منذ البداية ضد أجسادهم.
Around the time of puberty,
خلال بداية مرحلة البلوغ،
teenagers experience a delay in their biological clock,
يمر المراهقين بتجربة تأخر في ساعتهم البيولوجية،
which determines when we feel most awake and when we feel most sleepy.
مما يحدد متى نشعر بأننا في قمة النشاط أو الخمول .
This is driven in part by a shift in the release of the hormone melatonin.
وهذا ناتج جزئيا عن تغيير في إطلاق هرمون ميلاتونين.
Teenagers' bodies wait to start releasing melatonin until around 11pm,
فأجساد المراهقين تنتظر حتى حوالي 11 ليلا لإطلاق الميلاتونين،
which is two hours later than what we see in adults or younger children.
أي بعد ساعتين من التوقيت الملاحظ لدى البالغين والأطفال
This means that waking a teenager up at 6am is the biological equivalent
وهذا يعني أن إيقاظ مراهق 6 صباحا يعادل بيولوجيا
of waking an adult up at 4am.
إيقاظ شخص بالغ 4 صباحا.
On the unfortunate days when I have to wake up at 4am,
في الأيام السيئة الطالع عندما يتوجب علي الاستيقاظ 4 صباحا،
I'm a zombie.
أكون كالأموات الأحياء.
Functionally useless.
عديمة الجدوى.
I can't think straight,
لا يمكنني التفكير بشكل سليم
I'm irritable,
وفي مزاج عصبي
and I probably shouldn't be driving a car.
وعلى الأرجح لا ينبغي علي قيادة السيارة.
But this is how many American teenagers feel every single school day.
لكن هذا شعور عديد المراهقين الأمريكيين في كل يوم دراسي.
In fact, many of the, shall we say,
في الواقع، العديد من، إن جاز لنا القول،
unpleasant characteristics that we chalk up to being a teenager --
الطبائع المزعجة التي نعزوها إلى كون المراهق --
moodiness, irritability, laziness, depression --
تقلب المزاج والانفعالية والكسل والكآبة --
could be a product of chronic sleep deprivation.
قد تكون نتيجة لحرمان مزمن من النوم.
For many teens battling chronic sleep loss,
بالنسبة للعديد من المراهقين المجابهين لنقص النوم المزمن،
their go-to strategy to compensate is consuming large quantities of caffeine
فإن استراتيجيتهم تقتضي استهلاك كميات كبيرة من الكافيين
in the form of venti frappuccinos,
في شكل فينتي الفرابوتشينو
or energy drinks and shots.
أو المشروبات الطاقية أو المركزة.
So essentially,
الخلاصة،
we've got an entire population of tired but wired youth.
لدينا فئة سكانية كاملة من الشباب المتعب ولكنه متصل.
Advocates of sleep-friendly start times know
يعلم المدافعون عن النوم الهانئ لوقت البدء
that adolescence is a period of dramatic brain development,
بأن المراهقة هي فترة نمو جد مهمة للدماغ،
particularly in the parts of the brain
وخاصة أجزاء الدماغ
that are responsible for those higher order thinking processes,
المسؤولة عن عمليات التفكير المعقدة.
including reasoning, problem-solving and good judgment.
بما في ذلك التفكر وحل المشاكل والتقييم الجيد.
In other words, the very type of brain activity that's responsible
من ناحية اخرى ،النشاط الدماغي المسؤول
for reining in those impulsive and often risky behaviors
عن التحكم في تلك التصرفات المندفعة والمحفوفة بالمخاطر
that are so characteristic of adolescence
المميزة للمراهقة
and that are so terrifying to us parents of teenagers.
والمخيفة بالنسبة لنا كأباء وأمهات.
They know that like the rest of us,
وهم يعلمون، كما نعلم،
when teenagers don't get the sleep they need,
بأنه عندما لا يحصل المراهقون على كفايتهم من النوم،
their brains, their bodies and behaviors suffer
فإن عقولهم وأجسادهم وتصرفاتهم تعاني
with both immediate and lasting effects.
من تأثيرات فورية ومؤجلة.
They can't concentrate,
فلا يمكنهم التركيز
their attention plummets
ويهبط مستوى انتباههم
and many will even show behavioral signs that mimic ADHD.
بل إن العديد منهم يظهر علامات سلوكية مشابهة لاضطراب نقص الانتباه مع فرط النشاط.
But the consequences of teen sleep loss go well beyond the classroom,
لكن نتائج نقص النوم لدى المراهق يتخطى حدود الفصل
sadly contributing to many of the mental health problems
ليساهم للأسف في خلق العديد من المشاكل النفسية
that skyrocket during adolescence,
التي تزداد الى حد كبير خلال المراهقة،
including substance use,
بما فيها استعمال المواد الممنوعة
depression and suicide.
والاكتئاب والانتحار.
In our work with teens from LA Unified School District,
خلال عملنا مع مراهقين من مدرسة لوس أنجلس يونيفايد ،
we found that teens with sleep problems
لاحظنا أن المراهقين الذين يعانون من مشاكل النوم
were 55 percent more likely to have used alcohol in the past month.
كان من المرجح بنسبة 55% أنهم استهلكوا الكحول الشهر الماضي.
In another study with over 30,000 high school students,
وفي دراسة أخرى مع 30.000 طالب ثانوية،
they found that for each hour of lost sleep,
اكتشفوا أنه مقابل كل ساعة استيقاظ دون نوم،
there was a 38 percent increase in feeling sad or hopeless,
هناك ارتفاع بنسبة 38% من الشعور بالحزن والعجز،
and a 58 percent increase in teen suicide attempts.
وبنسبة 58% لمحاولات الانتحار بين المراهقين.
And if that's not enough,
وإذا لم يكن ذلك كافيا،
teens who skip out on sleep are at increased risk
فإن المراهقين الذين لا ينامون كفايتهم معرضين بشكل أكبر
for a host of physical health problems that plague our country,
للمخاطر الصحية المتفشية كالوباء ببلادنا،
including obesity, heart disease and diabetes.
منها السمنة وأمراض القلب والسكري.
Then there's the risk of putting a sleep-deprived teen,
كما أن هناك خطر اعطاء مراهق يعاني من نقص النوم
with a newly minted driver's license,
رخصة قيادة جديدة،
behind the wheel.
ووضعه خلف عجلة القيادة.
Studies have shown that getting five hours or less of sleep per night
بينت الدراسات بأن النوم لخمس ساعات أو أقل كل ليلة
is the equivalent of driving with a blood alcohol content above the legal limit.
كالقيادة بمعدل كحول في الدم أعلى من الحد القانوني.
Advocates of sleep-friendly start times,
قدم المدافعون عن النوم الهانئ لوقت البدء
and researchers in this area,
والباحثون في هذا المجال
have produced tremendous science
معطيات علمية ضخمة
showing the tremendous benefits of later start times.
تظهر الفوائد العظيمة لتأخير موعد بداية الدوام.
The findings are unequivocal,
النتائج واضحة للغاية،
and as a sleep scientist,
وكعالمة نوم،
I rarely get to speak with that kind of certainty.
نادرا ما تكلمت بهذا النوع من اليقين.
Teens from districts with later start times get more sleep.
المراهقين بالمناطق التي يتأخر بها بدء الدوام يحصلون على ساعات أكثر للنوم.
To the naysayers who may think that if schools start later,
وبالنسبة للمشككين الذين قد يعتقدون بأن تأخير بدء الدوام في المدارس
teens will just stay up later,
يعني فقط سهر أكثر للمراهقين،
the truth is,
الحقيقة هي،
their bedtimes stay the same,
مواعيد نومهم لا تتغير،
but their wake-up times get extended,
لكن مواعيد استيقاظهم تصبح أطول،
resulting in more sleep.
مما يعني نوم أكثر.
They're more likely to show up for school;
أصبحوا أكثر استعدادا للذهاب إلى المدرسة؛
school absences dropped by 25 percent in one district.
وتراجع الغياب المدرسي بنسبة 25% في إحدى المناطق.
And they're less likely to drop out.
وأقل ميولا للانقطاع عن المدرسة.
Not surprisingly, they do better academically.
وهذا ليس مفاجئا، لكونهم تحسنوا في تحصيلهم الدراسي.
So this has real implications for reducing the achievement gap.
إذا فللنوم تأثيرات حقيقية على تقليل الفارق في التحصيل الدراسي.
Standardized test scores in math and reading
حيث ترتفع درجات الاختبارات الموحدة للرياضيات والقراءة
go up by two to three percentage points.
بنسبة اثنين إلى ثلاثة.
That's as powerful as reducing class sizes by one-third fewer students,
وهذا يعادل خفض عدد تلاميذ الفصول بالثلث
or replacing a so-so teacher in the classroom
أو تعويض أستاذ متوسط لفصل ما
with a truly outstanding one.
بآخر ممتاز.
Their mental and physical health improves,
كما تتحسن صحتهم النفسية والجسدية،
and even their families are happier.
بل حتى أسرهم تكون أكثر سعادة.
I mean, who wouldn't enjoy a little more pleasantness from our teens,
أقصد من منا لن يسعد بمراهقين أكثر بهجة بقليل
and a little less crankiness?
وأقل مزاجية؟
Even their communities are safer
بل حتى مجتمعاتهم تصبح أكثر أمنا
because car crash rates go down --
لأن معدلات حوادث السيارات تنخفض --
a 70 percent reduction in one district.
بنسبة 70% في إحدى المناطق.
Given these tremendous benefits,
بالنظر إلى هذه الفوائد العظيمة،
you might think,
قد تتساءلون،
well, this is a no-brainer, right?
الأمر لا يحتاج إلى تفكير، أليس كذلك؟
So why have we as a society failed to heed this call?
إذا لماذا فشلنا كمجتمع في مراعاة هذا الأمر؟
Often the argument against later start times goes something like this:
لأنه عادة ما تجابه دعوة تأخير بدء الدوام بحجج من هذا القبيل:
"Why should we delay start times for teenagers?
"لماذا علينا تأخير مواعيد بدء دوام المراهقين؟
We need to toughen them up so they're ready for the real world!"
علينا أن نجعلها أكثر صرامة لنعدهم للعالم الحقيقي!"
But that's like saying to the parent of a two-year-old,
لكن هذا الأمر كالقول لأبوي طفل في سنته الثانية،
"Don't let Johnny nap,
"لا تتركوا جوني يحظى بقيلولته
or he won't be ready for kindergarten."
أو أنه لن يكون مستعد لدخول الروضة."
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
Delaying start times also presents many logistical challenges.
يمثل تأخير بدء الدوام العديد من التحديات اللوجستية.
Not just for students and their families,
ليس فقط بالنسبة للمراهقين وأسرهم،
but for communities as a whole.
بل حتى لمجتمعات بالكامل.
Updating bus routes,
تحيين مسارات الحافلات
increased transportation costs,
الرفع من تكاليف النقل
impact on sports,
والتأثير على الرياضات
care before or after school.
الرعاية قبل المدرسة أو بعدها.
These are the same concerns that come up in district after district,
وهذه هي نفس المخاوف التي تطفوا على السطح من منطقة لأخرى،
time and again around the country
وفي كل مرة عبر البلاد
as school start times are debated.
كلما تمت مناقشة بدء الدوام المدرسي.
And they're legitimate concerns,
وهي مخاوف مشروعة،
but these are problems we have to work through.
لكنها مشاكل علينا العمل على حلها.
They are not valid excuses
إنها ليست أعذار وجيهة
for failing to do the right thing for our children,
لعدم اختيار ما فيه مصلحة لأبنائنا،
which is to start middle and high schools no earlier than 8:30am.
وهو ألا يبدأ دوام المدارس الإعدادية والثانوية قبل 8:30 صباحا.
And in districts around the country,
وفي مختلف المناطق عبر البلاد،
big and small, who have made this change,
كبيرة كانت أو صغيرة، والتي تطبق هذا التعديل،
they found that these fears are often unfounded
وجدوا أن تلك المخاوف لا أساس لها في الغالب
and far outweighed by the tremendous benefits for student health
ولا تذكر مقارنة بفوائدها العظيمة على صحة الطالب
and performance,
ومردوده في الفصل
and our collective public safety.
وكذا على أمننا العام الجماعي.
So tomorrow morning,
وعليه، غدا صباحا،
when coincidentally we get to set our clocks back by an hour
عندما سنجبر على إعادة العقارب ساعة كاملة إلى الوراء
and you get that delicious extra hour of sleep,
فتحصلون على تلك الساعة الإضافية اللذيذة من النوم،
and the day seems a little longer,
فيبدو لكم اليوم أطول قليلا،
and a little more full of hope,
وأثر تفاؤلا بقليل،
think about the tremendous power of sleep.
تأملوا في التأثير الكبير للنوم.
And think about what a gift it would be
وتفكروا كم كان ليكون هدية رائعة لأطفالنا
for our children to be able to wake up naturally,
لو كان بمقدورهم الاستيقاظ بشكل طبيعي،
in harmony with their own biology.
في تناغم مع تكوينهم البيولوجي.
Thank you,
شكرا جزيلا لكم،
and pleasant dreams.
وأحلام سعيدة.